# Sanjay Raj

Contact: 9473474712 | Email: sanjay.dev.0702@gmail.com

### **Career Summary:**

I have more than 3+ years of experience as a Java Developer, focusing on developing, designing, and maintaining software applications. I'm skilled in Java, Spring Framework, Hibernate, and other related technologies. I can translate complex requirements into efficient and maintainable code.

### **Skills:**

- Programming Languages: java/java8
- Web Development Framework: Spring Boot, Hibernate
- Agile Methodologies: Scrum
- cloud computing services: AWS Services

- Relational Database: MySQL
- Microservices: Using Eureka, Api Gateway
- Version Control: Git, GitHub

## **Professional Experience:**

### Associate Java Developer | Nexmoo Solutions | Duration: Mar 2021 – Jan 2022

### Roles and Responsibilities:

- Create REST API to develop new applications or features.
- Debug and fix bugs in existing Java applications.
- Collaborating with cross-functional teams to design and implement software solutions that meet business requirements.

Junior Java Developer | PG Technoplast Pvt Ltd | Duration: Feb 2022 - Dec 2022

#### Roles and Responsibilities:

- Create REST API to develop new applications or features.
- Debug and fix bugs in existing Java applications.
- Collaborating with cross-functional teams to design and implement software solutions that meet business requirements.

Java Developer | Marcellus Infotech Pvt Ptd (Client: CISCO) | Duration: Jan 2023- present

#### Roles and Responsibilities:

#### Software Development

- **Code Implementation:** Write clean, maintainable, and efficient Java code using Spring Boot for various applications and Create REST API to develop new applications or features.
- Microservices Architecture: Develop and maintain microservices, ensuring they are scalable, resilient, and loosely coupled.
- **RESTful Services**: Develop RESTful APIs for various services and ensure they adhere to best practices and standards.
- **Third-Party Integrations**: Integrate third-party services and APIs seamlessly into the application.
- Cloud Services: Utilize AWS services such as EC2, S3, RDS, and Elastic Beanstalk to deploy and manage applications and deploy your applications quickly using the AWS Management Console, CLI, or Elastic Beanstalk APIs.

- **Security Implementations:** Implement security, including data encryption, secure coding standards, and authentication/authorization mechanisms.
- Collaborating with cross-functional teams to design and implement software solutions.
- Integrating third-party APIs and services into web applications as required.
- Writing clean, efficient, and reusable code following best practices and coding standards.

# **Education Qualification:**

Bachelor of Engineering (2018)
College Name: Bhopal institute of technology & science (BITS)

# **Project: Delta Airlines (Flight Reservation System):**

"Experienced in the domain of 'Delta Airlines' Flight Reservation system, proficient in handling reservation processes, ensuring seamless customer experiences, and resolving booking issues. Adept at utilizing reservation software, managing passenger data, and coordinating with various departments to ensure efficient flight scheduling and customer satisfaction. Strong attention to detail and excellent problem-solving skills in the dynamic environment of airline reservations."